still so much snow
I got some help from Roderik and Elizabeth
you can dump it here
hoo..! steady
Go on.
Yeah.
I got it.
bit more here
It's easier to spread out.
Okay.
There you go
Yeah.
More or less.
No, you rest on the thing
then it won't fall over.
there you go
Voila!
There you go.
I think it's like
just below where the cork sits
Yeah, I think here, isn't it? somewhere
Yeah.
All right.
You can do six bottles
the white bucket is leak
it has a hole in it
Oh, homemade
yea it is homemade
Yeah.
It's just a board
with some screws in there.
And then these, you...
Yeah.
I mean, it works. Yeah.
Spiked shoes so we can walk on the liquid concrete
how do they feel?
we will see what it’s like on concrete
Alrifht
Ready to pour the floor
I have some assistance
because it needs to be done quite fast.
It's a product that needs to be mixed quite thinly.
So with a lot of water,
and then you pour it.
And it will kind of self level
Here and there you help it bit
and you measure it if it’s level.
So we set up, an assembly line,
I'm going to do all the mixing.
got a bucket with a hole in it.
So just pour the water in there
and then it will drain itself.
So you always have
the same amount of water for a mix.
the time between the first
and the last mix needs to be as short as possible
because it cures quite quickly.
And then generally what is done
is, with a spike roller,
You roll the floor when it's still wet,
so air bubbles can rise up and go out.
But I didn't find the right roller
because it needs to be quite deep,
because at some point it's
going to be like 3cm thick
and at the edges it’s thinner,
because the concrete floor is a bit
going like that, it  cups a bit.
So I don't have that.
So I'm not expecting perfection
on the first time we do this.
We'll see how that turns out.
All right.
Looks good.
Want to grab it?
You get this one.
Yeah.
Got it.
Left corner?
The already feel that
the bottom is curing
Yeah, you can scrape it around, but.
but not at the bottom
yea i’ll get some garbage bags and, then we can clean everything up
Be careful.
We are careful.
the dad is scared
He's right.
It’s so great.
It's just so tiny.
above there is cedar
it’s cheaper wood
Yeah, and the windows...
how much were those, 1500 or so
wow! with salt?
a mocktail
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Without, you know.
An architect, without a project...
And somehow everybody just knows.
Yeah.
They...
You get the metal, you get the rocks...
Exactly.
Yeah.
passed down through times,
you know, also the houses in my grandparents community
were built like that
by people,
Now for everything you need to sign papers
Yeah. You know
sometimes... like, in a rural area,
It's fine doing things on your own
in cities, no
It's impossible, no chance.
No. But like, I get what you mean.
Because if you have,
like, a specific building style
in a specific area and everybody has seen
that specific style be built already,
like you've been there as a kid.
Yeah, exactly.
So then you just show up and, you know,
like, oh, but nobody's doing the reef
Okay, I'll do the reef
Exactly.
Yeah. It's it's how it works.
And it's beautiful
because I think heritage is exactly about this is about
building culture and techniques over time.
But it's not like a genius,
like one person invented something.
It is more like a modern way of thinking.
That a new idea.
One single person coming in
and being a genius, in the past...
we build everything together.
Yeah, it's much more of like,
an evolutionary process.
Actually, it still works like that.
But we have the illusion that it's like.
An architect that is coming
has a new invention or new idea, but
we are just, you know, the descendants
of something else.
So, yeah, this was her thesis.
oh woow! amazing, beautiful
I’m very happy with it
I'm really happy
with how the tree's turned out.
I tried something new
and I think it worked out nicely.
You can also put it in our car? Yes.
then you don't have humidity problems
Okay. Is that alright?
I can put some
paper down
My car is pretty full
but in the jimny, in the back
I don't know, if there is a lot of dew in the night
link to Elizabeth’s artwork in video description
this one is very wonky
you see! two seconds, really close
Pew pew pew pew pew pew
pew pew pew pew pew! Pew!
All right.
One is, finished.
Took some time.
Five more to go.
Although the two in the front will be easier to build
because they don't need a hinging system.
It can go up quite steep, something like this
for December and January,
when the sun is at its lowest.
And then also the
snow will just automatically fly off.
Don't have to clean them.
There's also enough space in front
for snow to pile up
without blocking the panels,
so it will be much better.
So the second one and those ones
will be also be slightly higher.
Yeah.
So there's going to be two steel pieces
on the sides with some different holes.
So I can put them on different positions.
So depending on like in March or October
I want to have the more on a bit steeper
but not too steep
because that's also the time
when the storms are the strongest.
that’s going to put
quite a bit of strain on them
if I would have them really vertical. So
they're going to be half way
during this period.
And just as the season progresses
I can put them up steeper or less steep
So yeah, but quite a bit of work
still to do.
Also digging on all the cables
so I can keep it clean with the trimmer,
you know.
Mostly it has to be built higher and stronger.
The floor is going well
there were some air pockets
after the first pour.
It looked very good because all the water
is just sitting on top.
But once it started to dry
you could quickly see a few air pockets here and there.
So I had to do a second run.
Now I have to wait a bit longer
for it to cure,
and then I can, I can grind it down
and polish it
to a smoother surface,
but I’m really happy with it.
It looks really... the color looks good.
It's a beautiful flat floor.
So that's going to look great.